This program is suitable
for viewers ages 15 and up.
[Goblin: The Lonely and Great God]
Subtitles by DramaFever
If a spirit inhabits an object that has
the touch or the blood of a human on it
若靈魂附在某人的舊物
或沾了血的物件上
the spirit becomes a goblin.
便會成為鬼怪
上過無數戰場 染過鮮血的長劍
And this was a sword
from a battlefield
with the blood of thousands on it
沾染上了主人的血更甚
with even its own owner's blood on
it, so it was only to be expected.
And only the bride of the goblin will
be able to pull out that sword.
唯有鬼怪的新娘 才可拔出此劍
And when the sword is pulled out
拔出劍之後 一切歸於無 便可安息
he will become nothing
once more, and rest in peace.
Of course, this is a cruel
deal for the goblin.
這是惡毒的神諭
而以不死之身重生的鬼怪
The goblin, which woke up
to realize that it is immortal
is everywhere and nowhere in
this world at the same time
在這世上亦有亦無
此刻也在某...
and even now, nobody
knows where he may be...
Why the hell are you laughing, girl?
笑什麼 死丫頭
Are you about to tell me, "He's still
looking for his bride, and it's me"?
此刻 也可能在某處尋找著新娘
-=第1集=-
而那個新娘... 就是我
你是想這麼說的嗎
Even though I look like this now, I had
hordes of men following me in my prime!
別看我現在這樣
年輕時可是俘獲了不少男人的心
下次來時若我不在了 你可別吃驚
Don't come back next time
only to be surprised to find me gone.
真是羨慕啊
Wow, I'm so jealous.
我真是老糊塗了
I'm just getting old.
跟你這個未婚媽媽炫耀這些
That's not something for me to
brag about in front of you, though.
Hey, that's not nice!
真壞
菠菜 白菜都給你算便宜了
No, I'm not! I give you discounts
on spinach and cabbage!
我還壞
是拋棄你的那個混蛋才是壞
The bastard who left you behind
and ran off is the not nice one here.
You do have a point.
那倒是
But you know, that story is too sad.
不過這個故事好傷感
有何傷感的
Ha, sure.
是一個浪漫而怨毒的詛咒
It's really a romantic sort of curse.
為求死而尋找新娘
I mean, he has to find
his bride in order to die.
神真壞
God is cruel.
神原本就不是好惹的
God has always been cruel.
自私 善妒
And he's selfish and jealous too.
God only cares about himself.
唯我獨尊
He's just like another
guy we know, huh?
和某人真像
Well, I'll be going now.
I hope you sell a lot.
我走了 祝您生意興隆
And you'd better be
here next time too, okay?
下次來 您也一定要在哦
危在旦夕時
When you're in a position in which
your life is flashing before your eyes
你要虔誠禱告
pray for mercy
with all your heart.
Because a god with a soft spot
may be listening to you.
-=1968年巴黎=-
可能某位好心的神
會聽到你的禱告
[PARIS, 1968]
I wouldn't recommend doing that.
換做是我 不會這麼做
If you run away from home now, you'll
live with worse people than that.
你若現在離開家
就會過上比現在更糟糕的生活
可能會再也見不到你媽媽
And you'll never see
your mother again.
你是誰
Who the hell are you?
Are you Korean?
韓國人嗎
I'm a more complicated person
than you'd think.
一言難盡
It's your turn now.
現在該你了
逐字逐句地說清楚
Go and tell him clearly
"You've adopted me, so you're my father.
So you have to raise me well."
告訴他 既然領養了我
你就是我的父親
所以 你該好好撫養我
去告訴你媽媽 讓她幫你
And ask your mother for help too.
And tell her you're in pain.
告訴她你的痛苦
What kind of bull are you spouting?
Get the hell out of my way!
你在胡說八道什麼
讓開
提醒你一句 那樣割脈只能廢了手臂卻死不了
And slitting your wrist like
that won't kill you
but it'll render your hand
useless, so be aware of that.
Who are you?
你是誰
看著他 逐字逐句地說
Don't avoid his gaze
and speak clearly.
Can you do that?
能做到嗎？
And what if he beats me to death?
Will you take responsibility?
要是被打死了怎麼辦
你負責嗎？
所以我先幫你弄斷了他的類肋骨
That's why I broke his rib for you.
你個混蛋...
You little bastard!
這是便當
That's lunch for you.
等談完了上學去
Go to school
after you're done talking to him.
第17道數學題答案不是2 而是4
The answer for number 17
on the math quiz isn't 2. It's 4.
那道題不能錯
You got that question wrong, so...
你到底是誰
Who... are you, really?
他是水 是火 是風
He's water, wind, and fire.
是光明 是黑暗
Light and darkness.
也曾是...
And at one time...
he was human.
人類
百姓稱他為神
His subjects called him "God."
He cut down his foes
covered in crimson blood.
闖過血雨腥風 殺敵無數
And he was a military man
through and through.
當得起武神二字
金信將軍萬歲...
- Hooray!
萬歲...
- Hooray for the general!
金信將軍萬歲...
將軍萬歲...
萬歲...
Step aside! It's the great
General Kim Shin!
打開城門
金信將軍 凱旋
Kim Shin will take off his armor
and heed the king's royal decree.
金信卸下戎裝
I dare you to say
that again, punk!
大膽 竟敢出言不遜
正七品別將竟敢對上將軍...
How dare some political
lackey like you oppose...
明君的叛臣金信 卸下戎裝
The criminal Kim Shin will
take off his armor and...
你竟敢...
How dare you!
好
I heard you loud and clear.
Wait there.
等著
Happy now?
可以了吧
逆臣金信
Criminal Kim Shin, put down your
sword and get on your knees
棄劍 跪下領旨
and heed the king's royal decree.
我非割下你的舌頭...
I'll pull that rotten tongue
of yours right out!
"Criminal Kim Shin"?
Are you out of your damn mind?
何來的逆臣 瘋了不成
失心瘋了嗎你們
Are you insane?
General.
將軍
逆臣 金信
Criminal Kim Shin, put down your
sword and get on your knees...
棄劍跪下...
本將軍要見殿下 讓開
I'm going to see the king.
Get out of my way.
- Criminal Kim Shin...
- If you don't move, you'll surely die.
罪臣金信...
擋我者死
Step aside.
讓開
救命啊
你們這幫傢夥
You bastards!
These men fought
for three straight nights!
我們以主君之名已戰了3天3夜
好不容易才從人間地獄活著回來
They were just on their way
back from that hell!
So how dare you...
how dare you bastards!
可是你們... 你們竟然...
Open the castle gates!
打開城門
Stay here and watch over the men.
守在他們身邊
我去去就來
I'll be right back.
They say that he's like a king among
the people and regarded as a god.
百姓之上是王
王之上是神
據說那神就是指金信
And his name is Kim Shin.
他打了無數勝仗 蠱惑了百姓
That man's endless ascension to power
is making the citizens rise up
他的權勢再三嘲弄王室
and his power makes a mockery
of the royal family's authority.
請以國法嚴加懲處
So please, issue him the harshest
punishment you can under the law.
他
He was able to see the blades
of his opponents quite well
雖能看清敵人的刀刃
但沒能看出年輕君王對自己的嫉妒和恐懼
but he'd been blind to the young
king's fear and jealousy toward him.
那是 指向自己的最鋒利的刀刃
And he was unaware of the fact
that the king's jealousy and fear were
sharper than any blade he'd known.
可惜他沒能看清
So he's really going this far?
真要做到如此地步嗎
所以不要再過來
Don't step any closer.
停下
Stop right there.
不管你有什麼理由 都停下
Stop all of it.
Stop right there and die.
If you do, I'll spare everyone else.
停在那裡 死於逆賊之名吧
那麼除了你之外 可以放過所有人
但是 如果再往前走一步
But if you take even one
more step toward me
你每邁出一步 每一個眼神
I'll kill everyone in front of you
and lay their corpses at your feet.
我都會殺了所有人鋪在你的腳下
向前走吧 將軍
Go, General.
我沒關係
I'm all right.
我...
I...
王妃娘娘 我...
Your Highness, I...
我知道
I know.
我真的全都知道
I know everything.
And if this is the end for me,
then such is my fate.
如果這就是我的結局
那麼這也是我的命運
所以你往前走吧
So please, go.
不要停下
Don't stop, and keep
walking toward the king.
去殿下那兒 將軍
Don't spare her
or anyone related to her!
你這是謀反
滿門抄斬 一個不留 這是禦命
This is my command!
Stop!
住手
還愣著幹什麼 讓罪人跪下
What are you doing?
Bring the criminal to his knees!
將軍
General!
Your Highness!
How could you do this?
殿下 您這是為何
就不怕天譴嗎
Have you no fear of the heavens?
It's not like the heavens
have ever taken your side.
老天什麼時候站在你們那邊了
罪人兇狠的眼神令禦心慌亂
Having that sinner's gaze
upon us is making me dizzy.
Strike him down now!
斬立決
這不關你事
This doesn't concern you.
將軍 將軍 將軍 將軍
General! General!
我想拜託你來結束我的性命
I want to make
a final request of you.
To think that such a day would come.
遵將軍之命
請您原諒
Forgive me, sir.
I'll be right behind you, sir.
小的隨後就來
任何人都不許替逆賊收屍
Nobody may retrieve
this criminal's body.
Leave it out on the fields to be
consumed by wild animals!
棄屍荒野任由猛禽野獸啃食
他也就值給禽獸果腹
Such is the only fitting punishment
for a criminal such as him.
This is a royal decree!
這是禦命
將軍 一路走好
- Please have mercy, God!
- Please, spare him!
將軍
我們的將軍
好可憐
我們的將軍好可憐...
將軍...
Don't pray to anyone or anything.
不要求任何人
Because the gods aren't listening.
神不會聽的
And on that clear,
sunny afternoon...
一日之中陽光最明媚的午時
he died by the very
blade that he'd wielded.
他死於自己保護的主君的刀下
-=孤單又燦爛的神 - 鬼怪=-
[GOBLIN: THE LONELY AND GREAT GOD]
[SEOUL, 1998]
-=1998年首爾=-
Ow, damn it!
You crazy bastard!
這種瘋子
Are your eyes only there
for decoration?
長眼睛來喘氣的嗎
You have a death... wish...
找死...
Hey, what's with you, bastard?
你這小子
是什麼東西
A wild boar.
野豬
What?
什麼
You struck a wild boar
with your car.
你撞到了野豬
Are you all right, sir?
Do you want me to call the authorities?
你沒事吧
要不要幫你報警
I just hit a wild boar, you see...
我撞到了野豬
so, um, a wild boar
came out of nowhere!
就是說...
野豬突然間竄出來
A wild boar?
In the middle of Gangnam?
野...野豬 在江南市中心
It's... it's a person!
那...那裡
Oh my gosh, what do we do?
Hello? This is 911, right?
喂 是119吧
I'm at the Yeoksang
four-way intersection.
這裡是驛三十字路口
There's a woman in the trunk of
a car here! I think she may be dead.
後備箱裡有個女人好像已經死了
I'm not sure.
She's not moving. Yes.
不知道 現在一動不動
I'm not sure about that. I just happened
to come across this car accident...
具體情況不知道
究竟是因為交通事故 還是...
I'm not sure what's going on.
You should hurry and come.
具體的不知道 請快點來看看
Yes.
我怎麼...
Why am I...
why am I there?
-這裡是驛三十字路口人行道
-我怎麼會在那裡
Hwang Mi Young.
25 years old.
黃美英 25歲
Born in the year of the ox
on March 1st.
癸醜年 丁巳月 乙巳日 辰時出生
Time of death is 08:32 on Friday.
戊寅年 乙卯月 己卯日 八時三十二分死亡
That's the information
I have on the deceased.
死因 窒息致死
That's you, right?
是你本人吧
Drink it. It'll make you forget about
what happened to you in this life.
喝吧 會讓你忘掉今生的記憶
What happens if I don't drink this?
如果不喝
會怎樣
You'll come to regret it.
會後悔沒有喝下去
I hope that you will leave your
regrets behind with this life.
不管是什麼樣的後悔
願你都能留在今生
A goblin?
鬼怪
A god of death?
地獄使者
That's quite a vulgar
disguise he has on.
戴了一頂俗不可耐的帽子
Your Lordship!
老爺
It's been 20 years
since I've last seen you.
二十年沒見了
Have you been well for
all those years, sir?
您別來無恙吧
Have you been well?
你也一切還安好吧
Well, I've aged quite a bit, sir.
我可是老了很多
But you're looking
as brilliant as ever.
老爺依然那麼帥氣
He doesn't look that cool to me.
沒感覺太帥啊
You punk!
混小子
This is my grandson.
The one that I've told you about.
微臣鬥膽向您介紹 這是微臣的孫子
Greet him properly.
問候一聲吧
Who is this guy?
-=劉德華=-
這位大叔是誰啊
So you're Duk Hwa.
你就是德華啊
I'm someone who'll be your uncle, your
brother, your son, then your grandson.
我會是你的叔叔 你的兄弟
繼而便將成為你的兒子 你的孫子
Pleased to make your acquaintance.
請多多關照咯
What does that even mean?
這什麼鬼
You seem weirder and weirder
by the minute, Mister.
真是越來越奇怪了
You brat!
混小子
Oh, I offer my deepest apologies, sir.
哎喲喂 微臣惶恐
He's an only child
and was quite spoiled, you see.
身為四代獨子 家裡一直嬌慣有加就...
But you...
不過你...
Me? What about me?
我
怎麼了
There was a boy who was born in this land
but was laid to rest in another country.
曾有個在高麗出生
後來長眠於異國的人
You're his descendant.
他是你遙遠的祖先
And you look just like him.
你和那個孩子長得真像
Which part, exactly?
在哪兒啊
Was that ancestor of mine handsome?
那個祖先
他長得帥嗎
Duk Hwa!
混小子
I have no idea how such an insolent child
came to be. My apologies, Your Lordship.
微臣也不知從哪兒帶來了這樣的混小子
真是無顏以對了 老爺
Worry not.
You've never disappointed anyone.
無需介懷
你還從未讓人失望過
But you know, Uncle.
不過話說 叔叔
Why do you keep using
informal speech toward Grandpa?
你為什麼總對我爺爺用平語
Do you have a death wish
or something?
你找死啊
Why, you little!
混小子
Oh my...
哎喲
Your Lordship.
老爺
I offer my deepest apologies
for coming to see you so late.
小人來得太晚了 實在是抱歉
I've been sick all this
time, Your Lordship.
小人要是早些知道...
I must feel the same way
that your blade does, sir.
我...這
氣數已盡
From this moment on, this child
will serve you, Your Lordship.
從今日起
這個孩子 便會侍奉老爺
This is my grandson.
這是小人的孫子
This sword is "Your Lordship," Grandpa?
這把刀
就是老爺嗎 爺爺
It seems that your subjects
have saved your soul.
看來是你的百姓的靈魂救了你啊
However, your blade
is stained with blood.
然而
你的劍上沾滿了數千人的鮮血
They may have been your enemies,
but they were the gods' creations.
對你而言 他們雖是敵人
可他們也同樣是神所創造之物
So you will be immortal and alone,
watching your loved ones die before you.
你會孑然一身 在永生不滅中輪迴
親眼看著心愛之人的死去
Not a single one of those deaths
will be wiped from your memory.
你便不會忘記任何的死亡
This blessing is the punishment
that I am giving to you.
這既是我賜於你的獎賞
也是你所受到的懲罰
And only the Goblin's Bride will be
able to remove that blade.
唯有鬼怪新娘 方能拔出此劍
And when she does, you'll be able to
return to nothingness and rest in peace.
一旦拔出此劍
你便會化為虛無 得享安息
Your Lordship!
老爺
There is a place
where I must go.
我要去個地方
Who goes there?
放肆
How dare you come into
a place like this?
侍衛都是怎麼做事的
居然讓如此大不敬之人闖進來
Hey, you insolent...
你這傢夥 這裡好歹是...
Y-you... are...
你...
I was too late, it seems.
我...
來遲了
Grandpa! Grandpa!
爺爺
Grandpa!
It seems...
看來你...
that this is the first punishment
that I am receiving.
便是我所受到的第一個懲罰
Please... accept me.
請您...
收下我吧
As of this moment,
I will serve you.
從今起 便由我來侍奉您
That was my grandfather's final wish.
這是爺爺的遺言
I became blinded
by my desire for revenge...
一心為復仇 蒙蔽了雙眼
and couldn't even ask your
grandfather how he'd been.
要如何過下去
我連一句問候都還沒能說出
And yet...
即便如此
you wish to serve me?
你還是願意嗎
It's quite nice to be able to enjoy
a view like this at my leisure.
心無雜念地看著這樣的風景 真好
And I'm happy that you can enjoy
a view like this at your leisure.
我覺得你能這般心無雜念看著這樣的風景挺好
Here.
給
You should have it, Your Lordship.
I'm still quite full.
我肚子還很飽 老爺您吃吧
How is it that you're full
when you've had nothing to eat?
又沒有東西可吃 你怎麼會肚子飽呢
I'm tiny, so I get full even after
eating the tiniest morsel of food.
我還小 哪怕只要吃一點也會飽的
You're much bigger than I am, sir,
so please eat that instead.
老爺塊頭大 還是老爺您吃吧
We can do this, then.
那如此便是
We're still quite
far from land, sir.
離到陸地還遠著呢
Neither of us will be full
if we share this.
要是分著吃 誰都填不飽肚子的
So is that why
you're insisting on starving?
所以 你要餓著肚子嗎
I'm a child, so I can go around
to beg for food if I get hungry.
我要實在餓了 會去船上幫忙幹活
只要稍微蹭點吃的便好
Do you think I brought you with me
just to have you go around begging?
你以為我帶你來 就為了讓你蹭口吃的嗎
Trust me.
相信我
I may be an even greater
person than you imagine.
也許我的強大遠遠超出了你的想像
Come, now.
趕緊的
Wow!
Your Lordship!
老爺
Can I peek in that bag of yours?
可以看看你的包袱嗎
We need to decrease
the weight on this boat, you see.
得減掉他的重量呢
Your Lordship.
Your Lordship!
老爺
Put that child down now.
趕緊把孩子放下來
If you do, I'll let you keep
your life at the very least.
如此 我便饒你們一命
It's clear there's someone among us who's
at fault for the waves being unruly.
船上的風浪起得很怪異
任我怎麼看 裡面都有不吉利的人
I'll sell you as a slave,
so give me your hands and feet!
就是你小子
我會將你小子賣去當奴隸 留他四肢健全
And as for this squirt,
throw him overboard.
把孩子扔下去
Do you know what happens to
humans who are lesser than animals?
你可知道人類若是連禽獸都不如 會如何
They meet the God of Wrath.
便會造就憤怒之神
H-h-he's a goblin!
鬼...鬼...是鬼怪
Please, spare us!
救救我
It's too late.
遲了
It sure is nice to be back
here at my leisure.
心無雜念 就這麼回來了真好
Why? Why did you do that?
拜託 救救我吧
If there is a god, please...
如果有神 求您了
please, save me.
救救...我吧
Please, save me.
救救我吧
Just anybody, please. Save me!
隨便哪位都好 求您了
Who are you?
救救我
I'm "just anybody."
我是隨便哪位
Please... please, help me.
求您了 求您救救我吧
Well, I don't know.
這個嘛
It's my rule not to get involved
in human beings' lives.
我的原則便是不干涉人類的生死
I... really can't
just die like this.
我...
我...不能就這麼死了
The one you're asking me
to save isn't you, is it?
看來 你要我救的並不是你啊
求...孩...只要救下孩子便好
Just my child, at least. Please.
You're lucky, though, to have
met a soft-hearted god like me.
你今天很走運
遇到了如此心軟的神
It's just that I don't want
to see anyone die tonight.
今晚我不想見到有人死去
[JI YEON HEE. 27 YEARS OLD. BORN IN
THE YEAR OF THE TIGER ON MARCH 1ST.]
[NO NAME. ZERO YEARS OLD.]
Snow, and rain, and...
雪
和血
flowers, eh?
還有花
- The Goblin's Bride is back.
是鬼怪新娘
[EIGHT YEARS LATER]
-=8年後=-
What do you want for your
birthday this year, Eun Tak?
我們家恩卓 今年的生日想要什麼樣的年糕
Round rice cakes?
Square rice cakes?
甜年糕
彩虹年糕
Mom. Can't I have a party now
instead of Korean-style parties?
媽媽
我能不能不要開生日宴了 直接開個派對呢
What's the difference?
Well, a cake instead of
rice cakes, for one.
有什麼不一樣的啊
年糕蛋糕不一樣啊
I want to blow out candles
and make a wish too.
我也想要吹蠟燭許願呢
I think the reason why my
wish isn't coming true is because
總是對著年糕許願 總覺得根本不管用呢
I've been making my wishes on rice
cakes instead of birthday candles.
Oh, I didn't realize!
看來媽媽沒給你準備生日蛋糕啊
I only got you rice cakes
because you like them!
媽媽是看你喜歡吃年糕 才給你年糕的嘛
All right, then. Let's throw you
a party with cake from now on.
好吧
從今年起 我們就開派對
Wow! You're the best, Mom!
也會吃蛋糕
哇 媽媽最棒啦
Oh, it's a puppy!
哦 是小狗
Huh? A puppy?
咦 小狗
Look at this.
It's spring again.
你看這個
春天又來了
Isn't that fascinating?
神奇吧
Ah, I'm so tired.
Mom, I got a 100 on
my English quiz today!
哎喲喂 好累
媽媽
我今天英語考了一百分呢
I'm super-duper tired because
I used so much brainpower today!
用了太多的腦子 超累的
Oh, really?
是嗎
Wow! It's cake!
哇 是蛋糕哎
Are we going to have
a party now, Mom?
媽媽 我們這是要開派對嗎
Yeah. Come and sit.
Light the candles.
嗯
趕緊過來坐吧
點蠟燭
Is it okay for me to light them?
我可以點嗎
You can do it since you're
all grown up now, Eun Tak.
我們家恩卓現在長大了 你可以點
Oh yeah.
I'm nine years old now.
對哦 我可九歲了呢
I even got a 100 on my English
quiz, so this is a cakewalk.
英語都考了一百分 這點事兒還不是小菜一碟
Where did you learn that saying?
這種話 你又是從哪兒學來的啊
You don't need to know, Mom.
媽媽你不用知道啦
I'm just good at picking up these
things from all sorts of people.
我就是透過各種人 學話學得夠好了
I think I might be a genius...
我看啊 我可能是個天才...
What's the matter?
You have to make a wish.
怎麼了
你得許願啊
Happy birthday, my little pup!
祝你生日快樂哦 我的小寶貝
It's not really you, Mom.
原來不是你啊
It's your spirit that
I'm talking to, isn't it?
原來真的不是媽媽
而是媽媽的靈魂
So... you really can see
everything, can't you?
你
真的都能看見呀
I was hoping that you
wouldn't be able to.
媽媽本來不希望這樣的
Are you dead, Mom?
媽媽死了嗎
Really?
真的嗎
Where are you, Mom?
Where are you now?
媽媽在哪裡
媽媽現在在哪裡
At Sageori Hospital.
我在十字路口的醫院裡
You'll be getting
a call from the hospital.
醫院會聯繫你的
And when you get there,
your aunt will arrive soon.
去了之後 姨媽馬上就會到
It's cold at night, so make
sure you have a scarf on.
晚上很冷 記得帶圍巾
Ask the granny at the supermarket
to go with you too. Okay?
去找小賣部奶奶和你一起去
You know how to get to
her place, right?
能找到小賣部奶奶吧
Go down the alleyway next to
the dry cleaners and then make a right.
從洗衣店路口往下走
就在一下去的右手邊
Oh, you're so clever,
my little pup!
真聰明 我的小寶貝
Don't ever look another spirit
in the eye from now on, okay?
以後絕對不要和靈魂對視
知道了嗎
I'm sorry, Mom, that I can see spirits.
對不起 媽媽
因為我能看見那些
But it's because I can see spirits
that I can see you now.
但就是因為我能看見那些
才能看見媽媽
I'm okay, Mom.
所以 我沒關係
Okay.
好
Thank you so much...
你能這樣看著媽媽
for seeing me like this.
謝謝你
I... I think that
I have to go now.
恩卓
媽媽...
媽媽現在似乎該走了
I love you, my little pup.
我愛你 我家小寶貝
Me too.
I love you too, Mom.
我也是
我也愛你 媽媽
Bye, Mom. Goodbye.
媽媽再見
媽媽走好
You have to go to heaven, okay?
媽媽一定要去天堂 好嗎
You have to!
一定
一定哦
Mom!
媽媽
Hello? Is this
Ms. Ji Yeon Hee's home?
你好 請問是池蓮熙家嗎
This is Sageori Jaeil
Hospital, and...
這裡是十字路口第一醫院
I know.
I'll head over there.
我知道 我會去的
I'm not going to make a wish.
願望
我才不要許願
I'm not going to make
even a single wish.
一個都不許
Nobody ever grants
them for me anyway.
反正沒有人會聽
So who would I even
make the wish to?
向誰許願呢
How is it that you never
seem to grow old, Granny?
奶奶怎麼都不會老呢
How could I possibly get
any older than this?
還能怎麼繼續老呢
You do have a point.
那倒也是
Can't you check up on my Eun Tak
every once in a while?
偶爾照顧一下我們恩卓 不行嗎
Spouting such nonsense again.
不要
Why would I check up
on your daughter?
你的女兒 我為什麼要照顧
Just every once in a while!
我說偶爾嘛
Give her some leftover
cabbage if you have any
如果有剩下的白菜就給她一點
and some spinach, too.
菠菜也給一點
You should've just died then. Why did you
have to ask them to give you more time?
所以 那時候一起死多好
為什麼非要多活這些日子
You're so mean.
你這話說的
You're the one who told me
to plead with them with all my heart.
明明是奶奶告訴我的
讓我虔誠地祈求
And you actually believed that?
竟然會有人相信那句話
And thanks to that, I got to live
for a bit longer before I had to go.
就因為相信了那句話
我才能多活一段時間
Thanks for everything, Granny.
謝謝你 奶奶
I came to say goodbye.
我是來和你道別的
I'm... going now.
我要走了
Who are you, Mister?
叔... 叔叔是誰
You... can see me?
你
看得到我嗎
Oh, my scarf. I didn't put it on.
Mom's going to yell at me.
圍巾 我沒戴圍巾
我要被媽媽罵了
You have it on already, though.
你明明戴了 圍巾
This is Ms. Ji Yeon Hee's home, right?
這裡是池蓮熙家吧
I came here since her spirit
wasn't at the hospital.
因為她不在醫院 我才來的
But how is a child like you, who wasn't
supposed to have been born...
不過怎麼會...
你本是不該出生的孩子
??
Did you, by any chance,
become nine years old this year?
你今年是9歲嗎
I can't hear your voice
at all, Mister.
我根本聽不到叔叔的聲音
What brings you here, ma'am?
您怎麼會在這兒
Go. And leave this child alone.
-走吧 別管這個孩子
-奶奶
Granny!
You're getting in the way of my work.
您這是妨礙公務
As if.
什麼妨礙公務
Why are you trying to take her now
when it's already been so long?
都什麼時候的事了 你現在才來做
I'm glad for this chance.
Better late than never.
現在能做真是萬幸
I have no time right now.
我現在沒有時間
That's your problem.
那是你的事情
Do you have this child's
name on your list?
這個孩子在生死簿上嗎
She had no name back then,
but she has a name now.
雖然當時那個孩子無名
但現在這個孩子是有名字的
If you have a certificate with
her name on it, hand it over.
如果有寫著這孩子名字的生死簿
你倒是拿給我看看
I'll hand her over if you do.
那我就放她走
If I'm going to get that, I need to get
nine years' worth of evidence on her.
如果要得到冥府的協助
就要有9年內所有的證明
You, of all people, should know...
您明知道...
I'll be seeing you again, child.
再見
小朋友
Granny! Mom is...
奶奶 我媽媽...
I know. And we can't
do anything about that.
我知道 那沒辦法
But you have to live.
你得好好活著
You have to move within three days
if you don't want him to find you.
你要趕緊搬家 在3天內
這樣他才找不到你
You've looked a God of Death in the
eye, so you can't live here any longer.
你和地獄使者對視了
不能繼續在這裡生活了
He won't be able to
find me if I move?
如果搬走的話 他就找不到我嗎
No, he won't.
找不到
That's why land is so important.
所以才說選址很重要
After midnight, a man and two women
will come for you at the funeral parlor.
過了今日子夜
會有一男兩女到殯儀館找你
Go with them.
跟著他們走吧
It'll be hard on you,
but you have no other choice.
可能往後日子有點辛苦
但你沒有別的選擇
But why are you telling
me all of this?
但是為什麼要告訴我這些呢
Because I've taken a liking to you.
因為我喜歡你
When she was pregnant with you...
你出生的時候
she was so happy.
我覺得很幸福
Here. A birthday gift.
這是給你的生日禮物
[10 YEARS LATER]
-=10年後=-
Excuse me.
那個...
Want to get a drink with me?
我們一起喝一杯吧
Sure.
好呀
This card worked up until
yesterday, but now it doesn't!
不是 昨天還好好的卡
突然就不能用了
So, um, Uncle.
所以我想說 叔叔
There are some unfriendly
guys in suits at the bar.
酒吧裡不是有穿著西裝
不太友好的男人嘛
I'm, um, with those people right now.
我現在和那些傢夥...
那些人在一起
So please, pick up the phone!
所以 拜託你接一下電話吧
They asked for your cell phone number
他們讓我說出你的手機號
and got really unfriendly when
I told them that you don't have one.
我說我叔叔沒有手機
他們就對我特別不友好
Uncle. Are you listening?
叔叔 你在聽嗎
Uncle! Uncle!
叔叔
Uncle!
She still eats by herself even
though it's the end of senior year.
高三都要結束了她還是一個人吃飯
If you feel that bad for her,
go and eat with her yourself.
覺得她可憐 就去一起吃啊
Are you crazy?
Why would I do that?
瘋了嗎 我為什麼要那樣
That girl sees spirits!
她能看見鬼
I'm more scared of her
than I am of ghosts.
比起鬼 我覺得她更可怕
At least you can't see ghosts.
至少我們看不見鬼
Look. She can hear everything we're
saying, but she's acting as if she can't.
你們看她
明明聽得到 卻還裝聽不到
Hey.
喂
Hey, I heard that
you're the Goblin's Bride.
喂 聽說你是鬼怪新娘
Come on, I know you can see me.
你明明看得到我
Come with me.
It's just that I'm so lonely!
和我一起走吧 我太孤單了
Please?
Hey, why do you keep ignoring me?
喂 你為什麼裝作看不見我
You evil girl!
壞女人
Oh, geez!
這個外形真是...
See? I knew you could see me.
看吧 你明明看得見我
Wait, so it's true?
I'm sorry! I'm so sorry!
傳聞是真的
對... 對不起 對不起 對不起
What was that? Why did she
apologize all of the sudden?
什麼呀
怎麼莫名其妙的道歉
You didn't even turn on
any of the lights, Your Lordship.
也不開燈
I was lost in my thoughts.
我想事情想得太入神了
These are the materials you
requested of me from the NIS.
這是你在國外的住處
-=大韓民國=-
Then...
Yes. It's happened, Your Lordship.
這麼快...
是的 很快
Duk Hwa is already 25 years old now.
德華都已經25歲了
I've pulled a lot of strings so you can
leave near the end of the month.
我已經讓他多去見識見識了
這個月底左右再走吧
If you leave now, Your Lordship...
您這次離開
this will be the last time in
my lifetime I'll see you, correct?
估計我很難再見到您了
I thank you for every second
that we've shared together.
感謝你
陪我走過每一個瞬間
Duk Hwa will be here
when you return, sir.
當您歸來時 德華會在這裡
I've been losing my keys
all the time lately
我總忘記帶鑰匙
so I've had the lock
changed to a keyless one.
所以換成了密碼鎖
Grandpa! Uncle Shin!
爺爺 叔叔
There you are, Uncle Shin.
I begged you to come and pick me up.
叔叔 原來你在這裡
我差點跪下求你來接我了
But here you are.
Do not interrupt an adults' conversation!
可你都沒挪過地方
長輩在說話 小孩子不要亂插嘴
Did you cancel my card?
You canceled my card, didn't you!
是爺爺消了我的卡 對不對
Yeah, I canceled it, you brat.
是你消的 對不對
Ugh, I was totally humiliated!
Do you know how tough she was to get to?
是我秘書消的 臭小子
我丟臉丟到姥姥家了 好不容易撩到的
Why did you even make me your heir
if you were going to treat me like this?
早知如此 幹嘛把我弄成富三代
Uncle Shin, are you going somewhere?
叔叔 你要走了嗎
- Where are you going?
- I told you to speak with more respect!
去哪兒
說了多少遍 改改你的口氣
Stay out of this, Grandpa.
Is it about that thing again?
About you looking for your bride?
爺爺 您先打住
難道是那件事 找你的新娘
Why can't you just say that you're
leaving to get married somewhere?
我說 去國際婚姻就去唄 為什麼不說出來
Why can't you say it!
為什麼不說出來
You're saying this kid will be here
when I return?
Uncle Shin, exactly when
and what time are you leaving?
等我回來 就有這孩子 是嗎
叔叔 哪天 幾點 什麼時候去
One male and two females!
Your breakfast is ready.
吃早飯了 一位男士兩位女士
I said, your breakfast is ready.
吃飯啦
Shut up, you loudmouth.
瞎喊什麼
Why are you blabbering so much over
the stupid breakfast you cooked?
做個早飯能不能安靜點
What's with the seaweed soup?
Is it someone's birthday today?
今天怎麼是海帶湯
Are you kidding me? Did she make the soup
because it's her birthday or something?
誰過生日嗎
給力 這傢夥煮海帶湯慶祝自己生日嗎
Yeah, it is.
How can she be proud of having killed her
own mom just to be born on this day?
看來沒錯
剋死自己媽媽的出生日期
還好意思慶祝
She's shameless because
she doesn't know any better.
Whatever she learned, she got it from you
since she's been with us for 10 years.
不學無術 所以也不知道什麼叫丟人
這話有理
Shut up and eat your food.
她在我們這兒十年了
吃你的飯吧
Thanks for wishing me a happy birthday.
謝謝您給我過生日 姨媽
This is why people say that
you should never take in a stray.
所以說 烏髮畜生不知恩啊
Being too compassionate is my downfall.
I'm the pitiful one here since
I've raised her in her mother's stead.
多情也是病啊
真替死去的她感到不值
Your words are a bit harsh.
我還把你辛辛苦苦拉扯大
您這說得就有點過分了
How is it harsh?
She may be your mom,
but she's my older sister.
有什麼過分的
Exactly. She and I are closer in
both heart and connection.
對你來說 是媽媽 可也是我的姐姐
所以說啊
無論是內心還是血緣關係 我離她更近
- Do you even know what you're saying?
- Shut up and eat your food.
媽 你知道你在說什麼嗎
Where are you running off to?
吃你的飯去
I'm not running off anywhere.
I'm going to school.
往哪兒逃
不是逃 而是上學
You're dead if you touch those umbrellas.
Meet me at the bank
with your bankbook after school.
敢拿雨傘打死你
You know what will happen
if you don't, right?
放學以後帶上存摺去銀行
How many times have I told you
that I don't have a bankbook?
今天還不帶來 你知道什麼後果
我說了 我沒有存摺
到底要說幾遍
Then where's the bankbook?
Where's your mom's insurance money?
那存摺在哪
你媽的保險金在哪
How would I know that?
我怎麼知道
You took all the money for yourself!
You even took the money from our house!
都被你拿走了 被你全拿走了
Why is she talking
so much crap this morning?
大清早的浪費口水
Just shut up and bring it
unless you want to get your ass beaten.
廢話少說 記得帶來
The bankbook disappears whenever
I need to go to the bank
不想被打死的話
and who else could it be but you?
在背包裡的存摺 怎麼一到銀行就不翼而飛
I'm telling you that
the bitch is possessed.
如果不是你 還能是誰
早說了 這女的鬼上身了
That's right.
There's a ghost right behind you.
What! You crazy bitch!
你說得對 你後背上趴著鬼
什麼 你這傢夥
My lordship.
Will you be traveling alone
this time too?
可是 老爺
這次也是獨自離開嗎
Yes, it would seem so.
No women I've ever met has been
able to see the sword.
是啊
我遇到的那些女子 都看不到那把劍
Which is of a great relief to me.
I hope the bride appears quickly for you
when you're in agony over the sword.
我是感到慶幸
您因那把劍飽受煎熬時 我希望新娘能早日出現
But if the sword is seen,
I hope no one finds out about it.
而像現在這般平靜時 又希望誰都不知道
That's just human greed, I guess.
這就是人類的貪念吧
It's a relief for me too.
我也感到慶幸
To still have you by my side,
and a full drink in my hand besides.
你還陪伴在我身邊
For tonight at least,
I'd like to remain alive.
而且有一大瓶酒
今晚我想活著
Shall we drink to that?
那就乾杯吧
When I was nine years old,
I told myself that I'd never do this.
我九歲那年下定決心再也不做這種事了
But I'm desperate right now,
so I hope you understand.
可當時太心急了 還望您諒解
Please help me find a job,
do something about my relatives
請讓我找到一份兼職
and please help me find a boyfriend!
請讓姨媽一家別這麼對我
請賜給我一個男朋友 求您了
Please help me find a job,
do something about my relatives
請讓我找到一份兼職
and help me improve my pathetic life.
請讓姨媽一家別這麼對我
請想想辦法 救救苦命的我
Even 100 won in my pocket
would be fine! Please.
一丁點也行啊
What in the world am I doing?
Who am I even praying to?
我在幹什麼
There is no god.
求誰啊
哪有什麼神仙
You're seriously not going to
make it rain right now, are you?
難不成還要下雨嗎
It's not even the rainy season!
這是場雷陣雨 還是苦雨啊
Will the rain even stop?
Will it ever?
這雨會停吧
Why do you keep making it rain when
I don't even have an umbrella of my own?
就弟弟妹妹有雨傘 為什麼還總下雨
- Was it you?
- Oh my goodness.
是你嗎
嚇死我了
Me?
我嗎
- Were you talking to me?
- Yeah, you.
我嗎
你是在和我說話嗎
Was it you?
對 你
- What about me?
- Were you the one who summoned me?
是你嗎
- Me? I didn't summon you.
- You did summon me.
什麼
把我叫來的人是不是你
我嗎 我沒叫你
- But just how did you summon me?
- How would I have summoned you?
你叫了
你到底怎麼叫我出來的
- I seriously didn't summon you.
- You definitely did summon me.
我沒做什麼啊 真的沒叫你
- Try to remember how you summoned me.
- Desperately?
你分明叫了
好好想想是怎麼叫的
迫切的
I didn't summon you.
I'm just able to see you.
不是我叫你的
Because we accidentally locked eyes
when we passed each other the other day.
只是我的眼睛能看到你
上次在大街上和你對視了
You're him, aren't you?
- What do you mean, you can see me?
- You're a ghost, aren't you?
是那位叔叔 對不對
能看到 你這是什麼意思
I'm able to see ghosts.
你不是鬼嗎
- I'm not a ghost.
- That's what they all say at first.
我能看到鬼
我不是鬼
一開始都這麼說
Who are you?
Why can't you see what you
should see right in front of you?
你到底是什麼人
- What am I supposed to see?
- Your twenties, thirties... your future.
為什麼本該看到的東西一點也看不到了
應該看到什麼
Maybe because there is no future for me.
20歲 30歲 你的未來
看來我可能沒有未來吧
Were you a shaman or something
before you died? Or a con man?
話說回來 你死之前是跳大繩的嗎
- My future, my butt.
- What? A con, what?
還是騙子
還什麼未來呢
Go to the light.
Wandering around for too long isn't good.
什...什麼 什麼子
請你往生極樂吧
徘徊太久不好的
- What's with those flowers?
- I thought you wanted me to leave.
可那花是怎麼回事
Okay, leave.
你不是叫我往生極樂嗎 還搭話
They're buckwheat flowers.
知道了 快去往生吧
But that's not what I'm asking.
Why are you holding those flowers?
蕎麥花
我不是問這個
Give them to me.
They don't really suit you.
我問的是你為什麼要拿在手裡
給我吧 和你不搭
I've never been told that before.
I've seriously never been told that.
頭一次聽到有人這麼說
真的是頭一次 真的
You can just give them to me.
It's my birthday today.
給我吧
今天是我的生日
A very depressing birthday.
非常憂鬱的生日
I get nothing but weeds for my birthday.
看來 我的生日禮物和草有緣
I got a napa cabbage
for my ninth birthday.
9歲時 我收到的是大白菜
But what is the meaning
of these buckwheat flowers?
可蕎麥花的花語是什麼呢
Lovers.
戀人
Why were you crying?
Job, relatives, or boyfriend?
Which of the three were you crying over?
你為什麼在哭
兼職 姨媽一家 男朋友 三個當中因為哪個
- How did you know that?
- I heard you.
你怎麼知道的
What do you mean, you heard it?
聽到了
聽到了...是什麼意思
- I grant some people their wishes.
- You grant people their wishes?
我有時會幫人實現願望
幫人實現願望
Like a magic genie?
Or a guardian angel?
像有魔力那樣的守護神那種嗎
Are you serious?
I knew it.
真的啊 我就說嘛
I knew you were different from other
ghosts from the moment I first saw you.
看你的第一眼 就覺得和其他鬼不一樣
- Are you really my guardian angel?
- I didn't say I was your guardian angel.
真的是我的守護神嗎
My mom once told me that everyone is born
with their own life dictionary.
我可沒說是你的守護神
我媽說過
每個人出生時都帶著屬於自己的字典
And in my dictionary, words such as
"Luck" or "Fortune" don't exist.
而我的字典裡
無論怎麼翻找也找不到幸福 幸運這種詞
- You know what I mean, right?
- No, I don't.
你懂我的意思吧
I'm asking if I can have
about five million.
不懂
就是問你 能不能通融個五百萬之類的
If getting me the cash is too tough,
then tell me the winning lottery numbers.
如果不能用現金
告訴我本週的彩券開獎號碼也好
Go and say goodbye to your family.
You won't get to see them for a while.
這也是願望之一
你和家人告個別
Keep looking for a job at a chicken
restaurant. You'll find something soon.
估計有段時間見不到他們了
在雞肉店努力打工 會被錄用的
Hey! What about my boyfriend?
我說...
Hello? Hey!
那我男朋友呢
我說...你在嗎
Ugh, what a poor sport!
真是的 小氣鬼
- I haven't met you before.
- Likewise.
似曾相識
But I have heard rumors.
確實如此
There are all sorts of rumors about me.
聽說過有關你的許多傳聞
我的傳聞裡有很多虛假的
What are you doing in my home?
You live here?
來我家有何貴幹
All the furniture you see is included,
so you just need to move in...
你住在這裡
這裡傢俱齊全 您只要住進來...
When did you get home, Uncle Shin?
你什麼時候回來的 叔叔
- Explain.
- The thing is...
this house is going to sit vacant
for like 20 years.
解釋
叔叔 反正這裡要空著20年
I thought about the money we could make
by charging someone monthly rent...
所以我就想 這20年得多少房租啊
我就以這單純的好奇心為出發點...
Do you even know what that is?
That thing over there is...
Don't refer to our new tenant as "that"!
你知道這傢伙是幹什麼的嗎
跟這東西...
你對新住戶太沒禮貌了
He owns tea houses.
他說要開茶店
I'm sorry, I apologize.
My uncle is socially awkward.
- Here's your coffee.
- Thanks.
不好意思 我叔叔社會經驗太少
請喝咖啡吧
- He hasn't paid yet.
- I saw the new car out front.
還沒收錢呢
- It's the new tenant's car.
- It's not my car.
院子裡有輛新車
And I've already given all my money...
那是他的車
不是我的車
錢也已經...
to him.
Then I'll give you your money back,
so leave.
給完了
事已至此 錢我會如數奉還 出去吧
I know you'd give me my money back,
but I've already signed the papers.
事已至此
合同書上都蓋完章...
- I hope that wasn't very important.
- That was just a copy.
希望不是重要的文件
The real estate agent has the original
and my stuff will be here tomorrow.
剛才那是複印的
I don't have any plans tomorrow.
正本在房地產公司 行李明天會搬進來
If you're done with your coffee, leave.
My hospitality ends here.
因為是良辰吉日
喝完就走
Go and pack your bags.
我的寬宏大量僅限一杯咖啡
If you're leaving for the next 20 years,
then you should start packing now.
你還是進去打包行李吧
You really want to start with a goblin?
20年的行李 夠你忙一陣子的
想看到鬼怪發怒的面孔 是嗎
I'm sure you're aware of what it means
to sign a contract with the grim reaper.
How about I take that young boy
instead of this house, then?
你應該很清楚與使者之間的契約是什麼
-=注: 跟死神的契約那種意思=-
不要這房子 帶走剛剛出去的那個朋友
Nothing else I can do.
Use one of the many empty rooms.
沒辦法
- Make yourself at home.
- It is my home.
有很多空房間 用吧
No, it's my house.
就當成自己家
是我家
If you think you can kick a goblin out of
his own turf, then give it your best try.
想把鬼怪趕出棲身老巢 我佩服你的勇氣
This is not the nice dinner
I had envisioned for myself.
It's like a horrible restaurant that
I've only heard rumors about.
還真是野蠻
如傳聞中一樣 是個低俗的組織
My bad.
喔 手滑了 本來要好好扔給你的
I was trying to get my soup.
My bad this time.
啊
我也是手滑了
I was trying to get you.
- "You"?
- I thought we had settled that earlier.
本來是扔你身上的
你
This. That. Hey. You.
剛才不是定了怎麼稱呼的嗎
這個 那個
喂 你
Lovers?
戀人
Lovers... what a joke.
切
戀人個鬼
-=招聘兼職=-
Hello.
Are you the owner?
您好
My name is Ji Eun Tak.
您是老闆嗎
I have a very upbeat
and positive attitude
我叫池恩卓
性格開朗 樂觀
非常開朗樂觀
so I can do any and every type of work
you can ask of me with a smile!
開朗樂觀
再苦再累 只要叫我做 我都能做
No matter how dirty the job...
再苦再累也...
-=一隻雞 參雞湯=-
-=原味炸雞=-
-=秀智家雞排=-
That was a load of crap
about me finding a job.
A guardian angel?
What a liar.
說什麼能找到兼職 狗屁
守護神
I should've at least gotten his number.
這人真是
留了電話號碼就好了
- See? It was you.
- Oh my goodness.
瞧瞧 是你沒錯
嚇我一跳
Why do you keep following me around?
- I didn't follow you. You summoned me.
- No, I didn't.
你為什麼總跟著我
我可沒有跟著你 是你召喚我的
If I had the power to do that,
I wouldn't be suffering like this.
才不是呢
我若有那個本事 就不用這麼苦了
How would I do that?
By shaking a bell or something?
我有什麼能耐啊
- Why would you ask me?
- Because you keep arguing with me.
搖鈴鐺召喚你嗎
你問我 我問誰啊
誰讓你一直頂嘴啊
Anyway, are you sure
you're a guardian angel?
我才沒召喚你呢
話又說回來
What kind of angel
are you, though?
你真的是守護神嗎
One that's been disgraced?
One that's on probation?
是哪一類的
什麼
One that's new to the job?
Who are you?
-=注: 出醜韓語的最後一個字發音跟神一樣=-
出醜
-=注: 反省韓語的最後一個字發音跟神一樣=-
反省
-=注: 會考韓語的最後一個字發音跟神一樣=-
會考
Is the part-time job at the chicken
restaurant you mentioned
-=注: 你韓語的最後一個字發音跟神一樣=-
你
叔叔你說的雞肉店 難道是養雞場嗎
actually a job on a chicken farm?
- No, it's not.
- Where is it then?
在養雞場打工
You gave me high hopes
as if it'd actually happen!
-不是
-那麼是哪裡
- You really don't know what...
- No.
說得好像真有那麼回事兒似的
叫人白抱希望了
你真不知道自己對我做了什麼...
Like I said, I didn't summon you.
It was you! It was!
It definitely was!
不是我
I've never had anything like
this happen to me before.
我沒有召喚你
是你 我說是你 是你沒錯
從未有過這種情況
Was it really me?
Really?
真的是我嗎
真的嗎
If it really was me, then...
what am I, exactly?
若是真的
Oh, I think I know now.
那我是什麼人啊
What is it?
啊 我知道了
Tell me everything that
you can see about me.
是什麼人
在我身上看到了什麼 全部說說看
You have a school uniform on.
What else?
穿了校服
You're pretty.
還有
很漂亮
I mean, your uniform is.
那件校服
Is that all?
You don't see anything else about me?
就這些嗎
I really must be a fairy
or something, like Tinker Bell.
沒看到翅膀什麼的嗎
依我看啊 我是精靈
小叮噹
Geez, he can't even take a joke?
Oh yeah, his phone number!
Damn it!
不就是開了點玩笑嗎
啊
電話號碼
In the name of the Father, Son,
and Holy Spirit, amen.
奉聖父聖子聖靈的名 阿門
Let us pray.
We thank you, oh Lord, for
blessing us all so much.
我們禱告
感謝天父施恩於我們
Everything we do is for You, Lord,
so please give us strength.
但願離您更近一步
您以慈悲恩待我
I got it! I figured out
how I can call you!
我知道了 知道怎麼召喚你了
But still, couldn't you have called
me to a better place than this?
那也不能在這裡召喚我出來啊
Are you scared?
I heard that Jesus and his
followers were good people.
你怕了嗎
Stop flattering them. Didn't you say
before that you didn't believe in them?
聽說這位神很不錯呢
I came by just in case
they might be here.
不要奉承 你不是不相信有神嗎
或許會在這兒呢 所以過來看看
Why are you walking away instead of
disappearing with sparks and such?
I can't do that here.
為什麼不一下子消失 走著去啊
Think of this as being
a kind of a dead zone for me.
在這裡不行
And don't follow me.
這裡類似非軍事區
What are you planning to
do about my wish?
不要跟著我
None of the three things
that I wished for were taken care of.
我的願望 你打算怎麼辦
They'll be taken care of soon.
Same goes for your job.
三個當中有三個沒得到解決
No, not that. I mean the thing
about me getting a boyfriend.
這次馬上就能解決了
You'll have to try hard
to make that happen too!
兼職也會
不是那個 我是說男朋友
那個需要你的努力
You can't just leave things like this!
這樣對待我 你會後悔的
I know how to summon him now.
I've got it now.
我現在知道方法了
算是拿到了電話號碼
Oh, I didn't think that
this would work.
Why did you do it, then?
我以為這個不行呢
Wait!
以為不行 為什麼還試
等一等
Did you just latch onto me?
你抓住我了嗎
Oh, I can't hold on
much longer! That's hot!
啊 實在不行了
I thought you'd be cold
since you were blue.
好燙啊
我看是藍色的 以為涼呢
Don't you know that blue fire
is the hottest kind of fire?
本來就是藍色火焰溫度更高 你這個文科生
Why not study if you have
time to fool around like this?
有空玩耍 不如多學習
You know, I've always been
at the top of my classes...
對哦
我自幼父母雙亡 無依無靠也一直拿第一名...
Oh, whatever.
Can't you just give me money
instead of being a guardian angel
算了
不要做什麼守護神
and call it a day?
I have to go because I'm busy.
能不能給我500萬 把我打發掉
What's got you so busy?
我有事得走了
Well, your outfit is
a bit fancy, yes.
什麼事
Tomorrow's the death anniversary
of someone that I knew.
打扮有些嚴肅哦
So why are you heading
over there today?
明天是我認識的人的忌日
Is that person's grave
out in the countryside?
In that place,
today is tomorrow.
那你怎麼今天就去啊
是外地嗎
那個地方 今天是明天
When are you coming back?
Tomorrow? The day after that?
那你什麼時候回來
There's something
I really want to ask!
明天 後天
Hurry up and ask, then!
我有話問你呢
那快問吧
I know that this is
a strange question, but
I'd like for you to not
misunderstand and hear me out.
我知道我這麼問 你會覺得很荒唐
All right, already,
so ask away. What?
但請你不要誤會 認真聆聽
When you first showed up,
I thought you may be a god of death.
知道了 問吧 想問什麼
一開始 我以為你是地獄使者
But you would have taken me away
as soon as you saw me if you were.
但若是地獄使者 一見到我肯定會帶我走
And then, I thought that
you may just be a ghost.
然後 我以為你是鬼
But you have a shadow.
可是叔叔你
有影子
So I thought long and hard
about what you might be.
所以 我想了想
And? What's your conclusion?
What am I?
那位叔叔到底是什麼呢
A goblin.
那你說我是什麼
鬼怪
Are you a goblin, by any chance?
叔叔 你是不是鬼怪啊
Who are you?
Who are you, really?
你是什麼人
It feels a bit awkward
for me to say, but...
你到底是什麼人
不好意思自己開口
I'm the Goblin's Bride.
我是鬼怪新娘
You know that I can see spirits, right?
I had this on me...
你知道我能看見鬼吧
我一出生
since I was born.
I think it's because of this that ghosts
keep saying that I'm the Goblin's Bride.
身上就有這個
可能是因為這個吧 所以那幫鬼
You can see it, right?
都叫我是鬼怪新娘
Right here.
看見了吧
You can see it, right?
這個
Prove it to me.
證明一下吧
You want me to prove that
I'm the Goblin's Bride?
Yeah.
讓我證明自己是鬼怪新娘啊
How do I do that?
是的
Do you want me to fly or something?
怎麼證明
讓我 飛給你看看嗎
Or turn into a broomstick?
或者
Do it.
變成掃把嗎
I'm being really serious right now.
能做就做
Me too.
我是認真的
Tell me what you see
when you look at me.
我也是
Are you trying to get revenge on me?
在我身上看到什麼 你都說說看
Tell me, already!
Tell me everything you see!
你這是報復我呀
說說看 你都看到了什麼
You're tall.
And?
個子很高
- Your clothes look expensive.
- And?
還有呢
衣服看起來很貴
You look like you're in
your mid-thirties.
And?
大概是30歲中旬
You don't want me to tell you that
you're handsome or something, right?
還有呢
該不會是想讓我說你帥吧
You needed to have
the answer that I want.
我想要的答案 你應該知道
But if that's all you can see,
you're not the Goblin's Bride.
如果你在我身上看到的就只有那些的話
You'd be of no use
to a goblin like this.
那你不是鬼怪新娘
你對鬼怪沒有效用價值
I'm sorry that you see ghosts
but you're not supposed to
be alive anyway, so be thankful.
能看見鬼 雖然很不幸
但你撿了一條命 還是感恩吧
You've already broken the rules
just by existing as a human being.
你只是我違背原則 插手人類的生死問題
出現的副作用而已
What if I don't want to be thankful?
Then you can just die
like you were supposed to.
如果我不願意接受呢
那就照你原來的命 去死也可以
You're so cruel.
這話說的...
Fine, then.
Let me ask you the same
thing I asked, one more time.
我知道了
Are you, by any chance, a goblin?
我再問剛才那個問題
叔叔你是不是
- No.
- You're not?
- I'm not.
- What are you, then?
鬼怪啊
-不是
-不是啊
不是
Who are you to decide whether
you'll be with me or not?
那麼是什麼
到底是什麼 敢判斷我的價值
I thought you wanted your life
to change for the better.
不是說處境變好一丁點也行嗎
I'm just someone who cares just
a little bit about your crappy life.
對你可憐的處境 擔心那麼一丁點的人
Tune into reality instead of letting
yourself be consumed by rumors.
面對現實吧
Because you're not the Goblin's Bride.
不要聽信傳聞
因為你不是鬼怪新娘
Wait!
等一等
I'm not finished talking...
我還沒說完呢
Did you just follow me
through that door?
你這是
從正門進來的嗎 跟著我
How... did you do that?
你是怎麼進來的
I grabbed the doorknob and pushed.
And then I followed you, Mister...
抓住門把手
然後推
跟著叔叔...
But what's with this place?
Hey, I just asked you a question.
How did you come through that door?
這裡怎麼這個樣子
所以我不是在問你嗎 你是怎麼通過正門的
Oh, is this
Provence Village in Paju?
啊 是坡州嗎 英語村那裡
But still, this doesn't
seem quite right.
What's going on here?
Where is this place?
不過 就算是那裡也不對啊
這裡到底...怎麼回事啊
Canada.
這裡到底是哪兒啊
Canada?
加拿大
Canada...
加拿大啊
You mean, the place
with the maple leaf?
加拿大的話
The one in North America?
那個
楓葉國
Is this really a different country?
北極光那裡嗎
這裡...這裡真的是外國嗎
Wow. You can do this too?
大發 叔叔 你還有這種本事啊
You apparently can too.
Who are you, really?
你也有啊
If this really is Canada and
you really have the power to do this...
你到底是什麼人
若這裡真的是加拿大 叔叔有這個本事
I've made up my mind.
那我決定了
- About what?
- I've made up my mind!
So, about what, exactly?
-決定什麼
-拿定主意了
I'll marry you, Mister!
Because no matter how I think about it,
I'm pretty sure that you're a goblin.
什...什麼
我要嫁給你
我總覺得 你肯定是鬼怪沒錯
I love you!
我愛你
Subtitles by DramaFever
[GOBLIN: THE LONELY AND GREAT GOD]
-=下集預告=-
Is this it?
The Red Café, just for me?
是這裡嗎?
Isn't it an honor to be with me?
為我而鋪的紅地毯
一起走 很榮幸
Who is she, really?
I'm someone who'll become
your bride in 200 years, Mister.
你到底是誰啊
兩百年後 將做你新娘的人
Keep the lights on, no matter what.
I want to see the entire room,
no matter where I'm standing.
估計她會繼續召喚我
無論在哪兒
我都想讓她看到我知性 整潔的樣子
Oh, how manly of you.
- Duk Hwa.
- Did something bad happen?
有男人味的我
Who said that I'd be your bride?
德華
Be careful of a man wearing
a hat! A black hat.
出了什麼不好的事情嗎
誰答應做你新娘了呀
小心戴帽子的男人
Am I dying now?
I just turned 19, though.
黑色帽子
我要死了嗎
Some people die when they're
nine, and some when they're ten.
我才19歲呢
9歲也能死 19歲也能死
That's what death is.
那就是死亡